Guide to the Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering records, 1917-2009.
Sibley School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering records
- Course Material, Correspondence, and Technical Documents
  - Three Way Values - Temperature Control Air Conditioning Set Up, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Time, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Westinghouse - Blueprints, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Westinghouse Correspondence, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Westinghouse - Turbines, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Westinghouse Turbine - Generator Lab Equipment - January 1947, 1947-01 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Yark Ammonia Compression System, Date Unknown (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Boiler Grates, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Sibley Boiler Water Treatment, 1934-1936 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo Forge Axial Flow Fan - Size AIDI W5, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Drawings - Aircraft Engine Lab, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Blueprints - Equipment, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Air Compressor - Worthington, 1922-1923 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Constant Temperature Room, 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Triple Expansion Engine, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Air Compressor - Worthington, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Waukesha Motor Company - Catalogs, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - CFR Engines, 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Centrifugal pump- 2 stage, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Commercial Eng. Laboratories - Cox Indicator, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Turbine-Curtis, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Dynamometers - GE and Wheeler, Froude, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 15-15A)
  - Drainator-Steam Trap and Frigidaire Leak Detector, 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Fluor Model Coding Tower, 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Franklin Aircraft Engine and information on Blowers, 1940-1959 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Gould - Tank and Venture Calibration, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Gould Centrifugal Pump Test- 12 HP Dynamometer, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Centrifugal Pump Research, 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - GE Refrigeration Model, Portable Set, General Radio Speed Camera, Gould Jet Pump, 1920-1939 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Heat Flow Meters, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Electric Immersion Heater, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Harrison- Heat Exchangers, 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Hill-Diesel - Instruction Booklet, Hornsby-Akroyd Oil Engines -directions, Hydraulic Turbine, Smith, 1920-1939 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Penberthy Injector Co., 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Lee Turbine, Yarnall Recorder, Gould Pump, 1920-1929 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Hercules Motor, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Laboratory Apparatus-working drawings - Light Wave Deflection Bar, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Nash Engineering Co., 1925-1929 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Vacuum Pump test- C 163 Ex. 7, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - 1930-1949 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Pyro Optical Pyrometer & Pyrometer, Engelhard, 1920-1929 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Dynamometer and manual on planimeter, Date Unknown (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - RCA Indicator - repair correspondence - 1940, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reverse Steam Testing Maehine (Gillett), Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Termocouple and Tachometers - 1929, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Toledo Scales - 1930's, 1930-1939 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Transformation Point Recorder, Brown and Tension Test Bar, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Turhine Tests - S. Morgan Smith - 1938, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Turbo-Feed Pump -Bethlehem - Weir, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Terry Steam Turbine & Mackenzie Steam King, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Uniflow Engine - Fitchburg, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Vacuum Pump-Stokes; Vulcan Soot Blower-Valve-Leslie Pressure, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Water flow meter - 1936, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Water Heating - rational design, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Water Softener - Wayne, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Water turbine, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Worthington vacuum and circ. Pump - 1944, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Air-conditioning units, activating aircraft engine lab 1947-lab equipment needed, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Aircraft engines, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Diesel engines- Diesel Engineering Symposium - 1948, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - combustion engine - 1949, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Diesel engines, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Fuel injection engines, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Gas Dynamics - 1947 - Prof. Kantrowitz, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Gas Turbines, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Rocket Engine, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Panel Heating - papers, course material- 1940's, 1940-1949 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Housing Research Center - Cornell- Correspondence - Glenn Bayer and C. Mackey - 1950's, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Solar Heating - Abstracts, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Building Research Congress - 1950's, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Grant application - Hugh Powell- 1960; "Measure the Thermal Conductivity of Nitrogen, Oxygen and Air at High Temperatures", 1960 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Lecture notes - Heat Power Engineering - 1930's, 1930-1939 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Ottu and Diesel Engines - notes, lecture notes, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Heat Power - Lectures by Prof. Barnard - 1920's, 1920-1929 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Heat Power - Prof. Ernsberger - 1926 and Course 347, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Mackey - Computations (347), Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Sol-Air and Weather Research - 1940's, 1940-1949 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Sol-Air Thermometer, Date Unknown (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - American Society of Heating and Ventilating Engineers - subcommittee- Sol-Air Design Data- 1945, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - American Society of Heating and Ventilating Engineers sub, committee - Sol,Air Design Data - 1945,1946, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Estimate of Cooling Load - Solar Heat Gains, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Estimate of Cooling Load - Solar Heat Gains- Manuals, 1940-1949 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Estimate of Cooling Load - Solar Heat Gains - Publications and correspondence, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Dust Control - Filters - Manuals, 1930-1959 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Dust Control- Filter - Publications, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ducts - Publications, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Grilles and Registers - Publications, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Grilles and Registers - Manuals, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Grilles and Registers - Manuals, 1940-1949 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Grilles and Registers - Manuals, 1940-1959 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Experimental Results Secured by Dropkin with a Diabatic Saturator, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Psychrometric Principles - Publications, Lectures, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Psychrometric Principles - Publications, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Psychrometric Principles - Papers, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Psychrometric Principles - Publications, Notes, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Psychrometric Principles - Publications, Notes, Correspondence, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Psychrometric Charts, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Silica Gel - Publications, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Silica Gel - Manuals, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Well Water Cooling, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Heating Coils - Manuals, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Heating Coils, Manuals, Papers, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Cooling Coils - Manuals, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Cooling Coils - Manuals, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Cooling Coils - Articles and Paper - "Solving Heat Flow Problems by Contour Integrals" by Rufus Isaacs for Carrier, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Unit Heaters, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Fans - Manuals, Publications, 1930-1959 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Thesis - "Preliminary Design of a Large Stem a Power Plant" - by Frederic C. Evans, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Electric Power Curves - part of Report on the Feasibility of Generating Electricity at the Heating Plant at Cornell - by Frank Ellenwood, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence concerning turbo generators, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1940-1959 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence concerning nuclear power - Mackey, Hollister, Loberg, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Sunlight Study, 1930-1949 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Fuel and Steam Rates - CU Turbines - correspondence, memos, 1939-1941 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Publication - "Fuel Oil for Diesel Locomotives" by Kettering of GMC, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Photograph for Prof. Dropkin - Mechanical Engineering, Date Unknown (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Dimensional Analysis, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Dimensional Analysis - Notes, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Edison Company Project - Research, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Special Testing Instruments Commercial Engineering Labs, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Thermal Environment - Radiant Heating, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Thermosyphoning Circuit, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Vapor Compression Refrigeration Systems - Chapter 2, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Clutches, Electric, etc. - Manuals, Correspondence, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
  - Devices - Fan Control- Manuals, Correspondence, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hydraulic Analogue - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Sol-Air Temp - Parmelee and Aubele, 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Variable Pulleys - Manuals, Correspondence, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
  - Variable Speed Driver - Hydro-Electric, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Manuals and Bulletins, 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Air Conditioning Principles, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Aluminum Co. of America, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Arco Paint - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Consolidated Edison - Panel Heating Project, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Dry lee Drink Cooler - Fan Model, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - NEP A Symposium on Heat Transfer, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Pierce Foundation - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Radiant Heating Fixture - Glass (Corning), 1943 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Radiant Heat Exchange, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Orange Crush Home Valve, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Panel Heating, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Refrigeration System, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Thermostat Bellows Type, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Turbine Generators, 1940-1945 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Wind Tunnel Project Research, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Detroit Edison Research - Drop Condensation I, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Detroit Edison - Drop Condensation II - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Summer Comfort Factors as Influenced by the Thermal Properties of Building Materials - by Mackey and Wright, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Periodic Heat Flow - by Mackey and Wright, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 35-36)
  - Course - 3503 - Heat Transfer - Mackey, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Course - 3603 - Fluid Properties and Mass Flow, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Mackey's Student Class Notebooks, Date Unknown (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Mackey- Engineering Math - Notes and Exams, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Proposed Program, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence - Professor Watson, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence concerning Orange Crush Project, 1940-1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence/Ideas- Orange Crush Co.- Mackey, 1940-1949 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Orange Crush-Dry I ce Radiator Water Cooler, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Refrigerating Apparatus - Orange Crush, 1940-1949 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Patent - Mixing Valve, 1940-1949 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Patent application - Sketches for Burling Co., 1945-1951 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence concerning Orange Crush Project, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Drawings - Apparatus for cooling liquids, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Paper/notes on Jet Pump, Date Unknown (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence/Sketches- War Housing Project - Mackey, 1940-1949 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Mackey to Director Loberg, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Mackey, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Professor Conta, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Professor Dropkin, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - Professor Andrae, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Professor Shepherd, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Professor Shepherd, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 23-24)
  - Correspondence - Professor Shepherd, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Professor Shepherd, 1956-1957 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - Bendix-Westinghouse Research, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Stow Manufacturing Co., 1946 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Bendix-Westinghouse, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 29-30)
  - Progress Reports - Tests of Flat and Relieved Fin Coils in the Cornell Draw-Through Tunnel, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Various manuals for electrical instruments and meters, 1950-1959 (Box 12)
  - Bendix questionnaires, manuals, articles and lecture notes on diesel and turbines, 1940-1959 (Box 13)
  - Various blueprints, articles and manuals concerning wind tunnels, fans, air compressors, blowers, 1917-1939 (Box 14)
  - Sample of Stationary Supplies- Sibley Jornal of Engineering, Date Unknown (Box 15)
- Publications and writings of and gathered by Frank Oakes Ellenwood
  - Diagrams, no date (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Thesis - "The Temperatures of Pneumatic Truck Tires", 1922 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "The most powerful giant in the world: the steam turbin"., no date (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Report on the need for additional steam-generating units at the Watkins Salt Company., 1945-03-21 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Steam-reheating-regenerative cycle, working papers - spreadsheet, memos, letters, draft, papers, newspaper, abstract of a paper, draft of a paper, lists, telegrams, notes, program of a meeting., 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Turbine Losses - comparative analysis., 1916 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Nozzle and bucket coefficients - notes., 1916 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Nozzle and bucket coefficients - documentation, computations, designs., 1913-1916 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lehigh turbine calculations for coefficients - notes, drafts., 1913, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - "The thermal performance of the Detroit turbine using steam at 1000 deg. Fahr." by W. A. Carter and Frank Oakes Ellenwood - paper and errata., 1933 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "Efficiencies of Otto and Diesel Engines" by Frank Oakes Ellenwood, Frederic Charles Evans and C. T. Chwang., 1928 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Copy of the journal of the society of automotive engineers, vol. XI, no. 2., 1922 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "High pressure, reheating, and regenerating for steam power plants" by Clarence Floyd Hirshfeld, F. O. Ellenwood., 1923 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "The specific heats of certain gases over wide ranges of pressures and temperatures: air, CO, CO2, C2H4, H2, N2, and O2" by Frank Oakes Ellenwood, Nicholas Kulik and Norman R. Gay., 1942 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - "Departmental and inter-departmental research in heat-power engineering" by Frank Oakes Ellenwood., 1942 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Reviews of Frank Oakes Publications - paper clippings., 1927-1934 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Paper clippings and pamphlets about happiness, poker, religion, political subjects, mathematics, health, driving, lexicography and cooking; postcard., 1934-1942 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Documentation about physical and engineering studies - articles, paper clippings, notes., 1930-1944 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - "Power: its application from the 17th dynasty to the 20th century", article published by the Morse Chain Company, Ithaca, N.Y., 1923 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Celebration of the one-hundredth anniversary of the birth of Robert Henry Thurston - program, copy of Science, vol. 90, no. 2346., 1939 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Text of a toast given in honor of Frank Oakes Ellenwood., 1943 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence of Frank Oakes Ellenwood., 1941-1954 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Thermodynamic charts, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Steam charts, 1914; 1929 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Chinese University Club of Detroit, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Graduate School - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Annual Reports and Faculty Meeting Minutes
  - Annual Reports to the Dean, 1949-1989 (Box 17, Folder 1-21)
  - Annual Reports to the Dean, 1989-1997 (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1947-1996 (Box 18, Folder 7-21)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1997-2009 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Machine Design Department Meetings, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Machine Design Annual Reports by Arthur Burr, 1962-1968 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Mechanical Systems and Design Department Annual Reports, 1969-1972 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Photographs
  - Faculty and Students, 1916-1917 (Mapcase-folder X-10)
- Engineering Quad Sundial
  - Professor Richard Phelan's Planning Drawings, 1979 (Mapcase-folder DD-12)